Finding Aid for Harlow Olin Whittemore Papers, 1905-1986
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Photographs, undated; circa 1909-1952
  - Negatives, 2 1/2 x 3 1/2; and 2 3/4 x 4 1/2
    - Hartland
      - Deerfield Center School, 1937; 3 negatives (Box 6)
      - Millpond Dam, September, 1940; 3 negatives (Box 6)
      - Miscellaneous, 1932; 1 negatives (Box 6)
      - Recreation Eall, April, 1940; 2 negatives (Box 6)
      - Waldenwoods Farms, March, 1938; 1 negatives (Box 6)
    - Higgins Lake State Park, 1934; 7 negatives (Box 6)
    - Highland Park (Box 6)
      (see other sized negatives in box 5)
    - Hillsdale
      - Factory, May, 1941; 1 negatives (Box 6)
      - Street Scenes, circa 1949-1952; 3 negatives (Box 6)
        (see also other sized negatives nos. 4-39 in box 5)
    - Holland (Michigan), Summer 1940; 8 negatives (Box 6)
    - Hubbard Lake (Box 7)
      - 1920, 1 negatives (Box 7)
      - 1933, 4 negatives (Box 7)
    - Huron-Clinton Parkway
      - Kent Lake Area, undated; 3 negatives (Box 7)
      - Miscellaneous, undated; 34 negatives (Box 7)
    - Interlochen State Park, undated; 2 negatives (Box 7)
    - Jackson
      - Jackson High School, May, 1930; 4 negatives (Box 7)
      - Oakdale Cemetery, October, 1937; 3 negatives (Box 7)
      - Shays Park, 1915; 1 negatives (Box 7)
      - Tourist Lodges, July, 1940; 3 negatives (Box 7)
    - Lapeer, April, 1931; 1 negatives (Box 7)
    - Litchfield-Stock Farm, 1941; 1 negatives (Box 7)
    - Ludington State Park
      - undated, 2 negatives (Box 7)
      - October, 1934, 9 negatives (Box 7)
      - May, 1941, 3 negatives (Box 7)
    - Mackinac Island
      - Or, 1926; 1937; 1 negatives (Box 7)
      - August, 1940, 7 negatives (Box 7)
    - Manistee-Infirmary Garden, May, 1941; 4 negatives (Box 7)
    - Marshall, Summer 1941; 2 negatives (Box 7)
    - Milford-Huron River, 1937; 1 negatives (Box 7)
    - Muskegon State Park, undated; 1 negatives (Box 7)
    - Napoleon, undated; 1 negatives (Box 7)
    - Oscoda
      - Auditorium, undated; 1 negatives (Box 7)
      - Au Sable River, undated; 1 negatives (Box 7)
      - School, undated; 1 negatives (Box 7)
      - Van Ettan Lake, undated; 3 negatives (Box 7)
    - Owlwood, undated; 1 negatives (Box 7)
    - Owosso
      - 1914, 1 negatives (Box 7)
      - 1915
        - Thomas Farm, 8 negatives (Box 7)
        - Welch Farm, 2 negatives (Box 7)
    - Presque Isle County-Ocqueoc Falls, undated; 1 negatives (Box 7)
    - Saugatuck-Sand Dunes, undated; 1 negatives (Box 7)
    - Sturgis-Factory Grounds, undated; 2 negatives (Box 7)
    - Traverse City, May, 1941; 7 negatives (Box 7)
    - Upper Peninsula
      - Amasa, 1923; 8 negatives (Box 7)
      - Baraga State Park, undated; 1 negatives (Box 7)
      - Chippewa County-Munuskong Bay, 1933; 4 negatives (Box 7)
      - Copper Harbor-Fort Wilkins State Park, September, 1930; 5 negatives (Box 7)
      - Drummond Is, September, 1934; 3 negatives (Box 7)
      - Escanaba, undated; 8 negatives (Box 7)
      - Gladstone, undated; 1 negatives (Box 7)
      - Houghton-Hancock, undated; 4 negatives (Box 7)
      - Huron Mountains, undated; 5 negatives (Box 7)
      - Iron Mountain
        - July, 1923, 2 negatives (Box 7)
        - August, 1923, 3 negatives (Box 7)
      - Isle Royale, August, 1936; 5 negatives (Box 7)
      - Keweenaw Bay, September, 1930; 2 negatives (Box 7)
      - Manistique, September 1930; 2 negatives (Box 7)
      - Marquette
        - Undated-Lake Michigamme, 2 negatives (Box 7)
        - State Park, September, 1930; 1 negatives (Box 7)
        - September, 1936, 2 negatives (Box 7)
      - Munising, September, 1930; 5 negatives (Box 7)
      - Porcupine Mountains, undated; 6 negatives (Box 7)
      - St. Ignace, 1935; 3 negatives (Box 7)
      - Sault Ste. Marie
        - Park, July 4, 1926; 1 negatives (Box 7)
        - Public Schools, circa 1951; 10 negatives (Box 7)
      - Sugar Is, August, 1936; 2 negatives (Box 7)
      - Tahquamenon Falls, 1934; 4 negatives (Box 7)
      - Wakefield, September, 1930; 3 negatives (Box 7)
    - Washtenaw County
      - Camp Birkett, 1934; 7 negatives (Box 7)
      - Cassidy Lake, 1934; 1 negatives (Box 7)
      - Huron River--Delhi, 1936; 7 negatives (Box 7)
      - Lincoln Consolidated, undated; 7 negatives (Box 7)
      - Pennington School, undated; 4 negatives (Box 7)
      - Pleasant Lake, 1935; 1 negatives (Box 7)
      - Sharon Hollow Region, 1935; 3 negatives (Box 7)
    - Waterloo--Camp Takona, undated; 6 negatives (Box 7)
    - Wayne County--Dearborn Ford Rouge Plant, undated; 2 negatives (Box 7)
    - Ypsilanti
      - Ford Lake and Dam, undated; 2 negatives (Box 7)
      - Normal School, undated; 2 negatives (Box 7)
Related Material
The Bentley Historical Library also houses the papers of the Gideon O. Whittemore Family of Tawas City, Michigan. These papers include business and personal correspondence of Whittemore, his wife, their son James O. Whittemore, and other members of the Whittemore, Mack, and Abram Mathews families. The collection also contains business and legal records, sermons, photographs, and miscellaneous papers, covering family matters, Tawas City, Michigan (which the family founded), lumbering, journey of the Mormons across the United States and settlement in Salt Lake City, Utah, University of Michigan and its branches, and family genealogy.